<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="1.6.5">
			<file name="items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/KimJongTrill/DnD-Homebrew/master/Aurora/items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
    
	<element name="Amulet of Lathander" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_AMULET_OF_LATHANDER">
		<description>
			<p>Your Constitution score is 19 while you wear this holy symbol. It has no effect on you if your Constitution is already 19 or higher without it.</p>
			<p>Additionally, you gain a +2 bonus to spell attack rolls and the saving throw DCs of your spells, and you can use your Channel Divinity feature without expending one of the feature’s uses. Once this property is used, it can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">constitution</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a cleric">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="constitution:score:set" value="19" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="cleric:spellcasting:attack" value="2" />
			<stat name="cleric:spellcasting:dc" value="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Belt of Giant Might" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_BELT_OF_GIANT_MIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>While attuned to this belt, your Strength score changes to 19. The item has no effect on you if your Strength without the belt is equal to or greater than 19.</p>
			<p>You can channel the giant's essence as a Bonus Action to gain the benefits of the Enlarge portion of the Enlarge/Reduce spell for 1 minute. Once used this property can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">strength</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">waist</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength:score:set" value="19" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Merchant's Medallion" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_MERCHANT_MEDALLION">
		<description>
			<p><strong><em>Merchants Luck.</em></strong> When worn (no attunement) the wearer gains advantage on the first persuasion check made every day used in relation to a trade (sale, purchase or barter).</p>
			<p><strong><em>Insightful Eye.</em></strong> When worn (and attuned) the wearer cannot be deceived without being aware of the attempted deceit. The wearer cannot read minds but will immediately know when someone is not being completely truthful and have insight into the degree/scope of the subterfuge in question.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Spirit Bound.</em></strong> When worn (and attuned) the wearers spirit/soul is bound to the diamond and becomes absorbed by the diamond upon death. When absorbed the spirit remains in the diamond until released. The soul is released when the necklace is worn by another creature and the soul determines that the creature is a suitable host and the soul will then take over the host body and imbue it with all its powers, traits and skills.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">soul</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
		
	<element name="Bracers of the War Mage" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_BRACERS_OF_THE_WAR_MAGE">
		<description>
			<p>These bracers are made of hardened Dwarven Steel and are imbued with strong defensive magic, to protect the Dwarven War Mages in battle. While wearing these bracers your AC is 14 + DEX.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">AC, armor, protection</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a sorcerer, wizard, or warlock">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:bracers of the war mage" value="14" />
			<stat name="ac:bracers of the war mage" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:bracers of the war mage" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Bracers of the War Mage" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Devil's Due" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_DEVILS_DUE">
		<description>
			<p>This +1 arrow has a icy blue shaft adorned with chardalyn razor fletching and matching head, can also be used as a dart.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Levistus' Ire.</em></strong>When attuned, this arrow adds a d6 of cold damage when it hits along with returning upon reaching or missing its target. Additionally, hitting a target with this arrow makes your next shot against that target have advantage, and a critical hit the target is wounded and loses 10 feet of movement speed and 5 feet for each after the first until their next long rest is completed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cold, ranged</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Psionic Amplifier" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_PSI_AMPLIFIER">
		<description>
			<p>Your Intelligence score is 19 while you are attuned to this Headband. It has no Effect if your Intelligence is already 19 or higher without it.</p> 

			<p>It also grants you telepathy (120ft) and you can freely choose to have the headband glow with a purplish inner light (15 bright/15 dim) while you are attuned to it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">intelligence, telepathy</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">waist</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence:score:set" value="19" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Wand of Winter Storms" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_WAND_OF_WINTER_STORMS">
		<description>
			<p>This wand has 5 charges and is made of translucent crystal resembling a slender icicle. While holding it, you can use an action to expend 1 or more of its charges to cast the *ice storm* spell (save DC 17) from it. For 1 charge, you cast the 4th-level version of the spell. You can increase the spell slot level by one for each additional charge you expend.</p> 
			

			<p>The wand regains 1d4 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the wand's last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the wand melts into water and is destroyed.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM" />
			</div>
		</description>
			
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">wand, ice storm</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">hand</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>

	</element>
	
	<element name="Dwarven Maul of Thunder" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_DMT">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This hand sized maul is made of Dwarven Steel inscribed with thunder runes, it hums with a light buzz. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. It has the thrown property with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. The damage the weapon deals is thunder, and after a throw the hammer returns to the thrower's hand like a lightning bolt. </p>
			<p>Once per day as an Action you can speak the command phrase "BY ODINS BEARD" and throw the hammer at a target or an unoccupied space, if at a target make an attack roll, on hit or miss any creature within 20 feet of the impact must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or take 4d6 lightning and 4d6 lightning strikes the area and the hammer crashes with a thunderclap. Once used this property can't be used again until the next dawn. In the meantime, the hammer can still be used as a magic weapon.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">maul, thunder</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Mace</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Mind Lance" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_MIND_LANCE">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_PIERCING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. It has the thrown property with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet.</p>
			<p>Attuning to the sword establishes a link between you and the weapon becoming an extension of yourself; you gain proficency with this rapier, you are unable to be forcefully disarmed of the weapon, immediately after an attack the weapon flies back to your hand, and it deals an extra 1d8 psychic damage on hit as it draws on your psionic abilities to inflict mental damage. </p>
			<p>While you are attuned to this sword your Intelligence score is 20, unless already higher and you also gain telepathy with any target you can see.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="rapier">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a Psionically inclined person">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Rapier</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence:score:set" value="20" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		
	<element name="Wand of the Weavestepper" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_WAND_WEAVESTEPPER">
		<description>
			<p>This wand is made from many rare woods twisted and fused together using the raw power of the Weave by the Witch Neia Kelxisys, Vekzian Hero of the Great War. The wand was her chosen tool of destruction when facing off against the warring nations of Kol and Eshea allowing her to move among the battlefield with ease.</p>
			<p>You have advantage on initiative rolls while you are holding the wand. In addition whenever you use a spell slot to cast a spell, you can immediately teleport to an unoccupied space you can see within 15 feet of you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wands</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="type">Wand</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a spellcaster">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_INITIATIVE_ADVANTAGE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Adventurers Initiative ID" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_AIID">		
		<description>
			<p>The Adventurers Initiative ID is keyed to each individual Adventurer and functions as your pass around Térûvia as it is used to reap any of the benefits that come with being and Adventurer like lodging, rations, ammunition, and basic components. It also functions as a coin purse for the keyed Adventurer storing all coin one might encounter and converting between Silver, Gold, and Platinum at will. The ID also lets the Adventurer know when the damage or effect they may be trying to inflict on a target is useful or not calling out Immunities and Resistances along with Vulnerabilities.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Adventurer's Guide to Térûvia" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_AGT_ID">		
		<description>
			<p>The Adventurer's Guide to Térûvia contains the basic knowledge an Adventurer would need to navigate Térûvia. In addition to information the book contains a map with live tracking of the book's location to aid in navigation, along with the forms needed for reports and the means to send them via transport slot on the back of the cover. This handbook, can't be damaged by fire, acid, or immersion in water. In addition, the book doesn't deteriorate with age.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Sword of The Elements" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_SOTE">
		<description>
			<p>This item appears to be a longsword hilt with a place for a small badge on the bottom. While grasping the hilt, you can use a bonus action to cause a blade of pure energy to spring into existence, or make the blade disappear. While the blade exists, this magic longsword has the finesse property and deals force instead of slashing. If you are proficient with shortswords or longswords, you are proficient with the <em>Sword of the Elements</em>.</p>
			<p class="indent">After the Badge of the Tribunal is put into the slot you can attune to the item and you gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon. Additionally, when you hit an elemental with it, that target takes an extra 1d8 force damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword,force</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Crystal Greataxe" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_AUGUSTE">
		<description>
			<p>This Crystal Greataxe was passed down through the generations of the Auguste family lineage since early in the Great War passing from warrior to warrior eventually to Logen, who met the orginal owner of the axe, Auguste the Crystal Dragon. Auguste bonded Logen to the axe making it tied to his existence rather than himself before he was killed by Gorotto.</p>
			<p><b><i>Slumbering.</i></b> Whenever you roll a 20 on your attack roll with this weapon, each creature of your choice within 5 feet of the target takes 5 damage of the type dealt by the dragon’s breath weapon.</p>
			<p><b><i>Stirring.</i></b> The Stirring weapon has the Slumbering property. In addition, you gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made using the weapon. On a hit, the weapon deals an extra 1d6 damage of the type dealt by the dragon’s breath weapon.</p>
			<p><b><i>Wakened.</i></b> The Wakened weapon has the Slumbering property, and it improves on the Stirring property. The bonus to attack and damage rolls increases to +2, and the extra damage dealt by the weapon increases to 2d6.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, you can unleash a 30-foot cone of destructive energy from the weapon. Each creature in that area must make a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw, taking 8d6 damage of the type dealt by the dragon’s breath weapon on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. Once this action is used, it can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">hoard, draconic, breath weapon</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greataxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greataxe</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Divinium Armor" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_DIVINIUM_ARMOR">
		<description>
			<p>This suit of armor is reinforced with a magically enhanced metal alloy called Divinium, an alloy of Ethereum and Adamantine bonded by magic. While you're wearing the armor, any critical hit against you becomes a normal hit. In addition, when you are subjected to a magical effect that allows you to make a Strength or Constitution saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>		
			<set name="keywords">medium, heavy</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="medium or heavy, but not hide">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="armor">(ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_MEDIUM||ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY),!Hide</set>
			<set name="name-format">Divinium {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Staff of the Dryad" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_DRYAD_STAFF">
		<description>
			<p>This staff can be wielded as a magic quarterstaff that grants a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it.</p>
			<p>The staff has 5 charges for the following properties. It regains 1d4 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff loses its properties and becomes a nonmagical quarterstaff.</p>
			<p>You can use an action to expend 1 or more of the staff's charges to cast one of the following spells from it, using your spell save DC: entangle (1 charge), pass without trace (2 charges), barkskin (2 charges), locate animals or plants (1 charge), speak with animals (1 charge), or speak with plants (1 charge). You can also use an action to cast the druidcraft spell from the staff without using any charges.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Tree Form.</em></strong> You can use an action to plant one end of the staff in fertile earth and expend 1 charge to transform the staff into a healthy tree. The tree is 60 feet tall and has a 5-foot-diameter trunk, and its branches at the top spread out in a 20-foot radius. The tree appears ordinary but radiates a faint aura of transmutation magic if targeted by detect magic. While touching the tree and using another action to speak its command word, you return the staff to its normal form. Any creature in the tree falls when it reverts to a staff.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a spellcaster">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="charges">5</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTANGLE" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_ANIMALS_OR_PLANTS" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Skyrider's Board" type="Magic Item" source="KimJongTrill’s Custom Content" id="ID_KJT_CC_SKYRIDER_BOARD">
		<description>
			<p>The Skyrider's Board is a common tool among the Air Zashniik with each of their warriors needing to undergo a trip to the Plane of Air to retrieve the reagents, this one belonged to Gustav Breeze Chief of the Air Zashnik.</p>
			<p>While you are mounted on the Skyrider's Board, you can use an action to cast the levitate spell on yourself at will. The board casts feather fall on you anytime you fall when mounted.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">skateboard, skyrider</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="charges">2</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
